export const itQuestions = [
	{
		question:
			"當收到信件前有什麼樣的註記,表示你應該對封信提高警覺, 因為信件的來源是公司外部? What text annotation, when present before a letter, should alert you to exercise caution as the letter originates from outside the company?",
		category: "it",
		answer: ["External"],
	},
	{
		question:
			"請問這個訓練能否讓你在開啟 External 信件前多一分警覺? Can this training make you more vigilant before opening an External email?",
		category: "it",
		answer: ["是Yes"],
	},
	{
		question:
			"保護資安的三不政策是? What is the Three Nos policy for protecting cybersecurity?",
		category: "it",
		answer: ["以上皆是 All of the above."],
	},
	{
		question:
			"公司不定期的執行社交工程演練（發送釣魚信件給員工）的目的並不是要? The purpose of the company's occasional execution of social engineering drills (sending phishing emails to employees) is not to:?",
		category: "it",
		answer: ["惡整員工 Prank employees."],
	},
	{
		question: "何謂社交工程? What is Social Engineering?",
		category: "it",
		answer: [
			"利用人性弱點，透過溝通欺騙技倆，以獲取帳號、通行碼、身分證號或其他機敏資料，來突破個人、企業的資通安全防護，進行非法的存取與破壞行為。Utilizing human weaknesses, employing deceptive communication techniques to obtain sensitive information such as account numbers, passwords, ID numbers, or other confidential data, to breach personal and corporate cybersecurity defenses for unauthorized access and malicious activities.",
		],
	},
	{
		question:
			"收到External信件後不應該作的事?What shouldn't you do after receiving an External email?",
		category: "it",
		answer: [
			"漠視公司的訓練,長官的提示,EIP的輪撥,不管會造成任何損失都與我無關,我就是要任性的去點選連結並輸入資料.Ignore the company's training, supervisor's prompts, EIP's reminders, regardless of any resulting losses, it has nothing to do with me, I will stubbornly click on links and enter data.",
		],
	},
	{
		question:
			"你知道公司大約間隔多久會發送釣魚信件給你? How often does the company send phishing emails to you?",
		category: "it",
		answer: ["一季1次 once per quarter."],
	},
	{
		question:
			"你你知道當你點選了不明的連結可能有什麼後果? Do you know what consequences may arise when you click on an unknown link?",
		category: "it",
		answer: [
			"下載了病毒 Downloading a virus.",
			"下載了木馬程式 Downloading a trojan horse program.",
			"被入侵後造成全公司當機無法營運 Causing a company-wide system crash.",
			"被入侵後造成公司員工資料或旅客資料被偷盗 Company employee or traveler data theft after intrusion.",
		],
	},
	{
		question:
			"你知道當你點選了不明的連結, 還在網頁上輸入了個人資料 可能導致什麼結果? Do you know what consequences may arise when you click on an unknown link and input personal information on the webpage?",
		category: "it",
		answer: [
			"你的帳號/密碼被對方偷走了 Your account/password being stolen.",
			"對方得到了你輸入的身份證字號/電話/生日 Scam groups obtaining your entered ID number/phone number/birthday.",
			"詐騙集團會運用上述資料對你進行詐騙行為 Scam groups using the above information to scam you.",
			"詐騙集團會運用上述資料對你的家人進行詐騙行為 Scam groups using the above information to scam your family members.",
		],
	},
	{
		question:
			"當在公司的信箱裡看到信件被標示為外部,下列那些可能是信件的來源? When a letter in the company mailbox is marked as external, which of the following could be the source of the letter?",
		category: "it",
		answer: [
			"同事用 Yahoo/Gmail 寄來的信 An email from a colleague using Yahoo/Gmail.",
			"駭客寄來的信 An email from a hacker.",
			"詐騙集團寄來的信 An email from a scam group.",
		],
	},
	{
		question:
			"以下何者非建議使用的網頁瀏覽器? Which of the following is not a recommended web browser?",
		category: "it",
		answer: ["IE"],
	},
	{
		question:
			"以下何種網址代表有加密機制，且通過認證，意謂瀏覽更加安全? Which of the following URLs means it is with encryption and is more secure?",
		category: "it",
		answer: ["HTTPS"],
	},
	{
		question:
			"下列何者為真實的apple.com連結? Which of the following is a real apple.com link?",
		category: "it",
		answer: ["以上皆否 none of the above"],
	},
	{
		question:
			"收到一封沒看過的email地址來信，內容包含了一個URL超連結，請問應如何處理? I received a letter from an email address that I have not seen, and the content contains a URL hyperlink. What should I do?",
		category: "it",
		answer: ["以上皆是 All of the above"],
	},
	{
		question:
			"https://calec.china-airlines.com/echeckin_tn/eCheckin_tw.aspx 以上網址何者稱為根網址? https://calec.china-airlines.com/echeckin_tn/eCheckin_tw.aspx Which of the above URLs is called the root domain?",
		category: "it",
		answer: ["china-airlines.com"],
	},
	{
		question:
			"如何在 iNotes 預覽信件連結? How to preview the letter link in iNotes?",
		category: "it",
		answer: [
			"滑鼠移到連結上方，不要點擊，下方即顯示其真實網址，並從根網址判讀其可信度 Move the mouse over the link, do not click, the real URL will be displayed below, and its credibility will be judged from the root URL",
		],
	},
	{
		question:
			"下列何種網址是唯一且絕對的，且為判斷網頁真偽的重要依據? Which of the following URLs is one and only, and is important for Determining the authenticity of websites?",
		category: "it",
		answer: ["根網址 Root domain"],
	},
	{
		question:
			"釣魚信件常以何種方式攻擊使用者電腦? How do phishing emails attack users' computers?",
		category: "it",
		answer: ["以上皆是 All of the above"],
	},
	{
		question:
			"以下何者為安全上網技巧?(多選) Which of the following is a safe online technique?",
		category: "it",
		answer: [
			"確實設定瀏覽器的隱私和安全 Firmly set browser privacy and security",
			"避免使用同一組帳號密碼 Avoid using the same set of account passwords",
			"注意信件中的短網址連結 be aware of short URLs",
			"使用Google安全瀏覽狀態確認網站的可信度 Using Googles transparency report application to check the authenticity of a website",
		],
	},
	{
		question:
			"下列安全觀念，何者正確?(多選) Which of the following cybersecurity concepts is correct?",
		category: "it",
		answer: [
			"使用瀏覽器時，應定時更新，且不再使用Internet explorer。 When using a browser, it should be updated regularly, and Internet explorer should no longer be used",
			"當新註冊某個網站會員時，應避開使用和重要系統相同的帳號密碼。When newly registering to a website, you should avoid using the same account password as the important systems.",
			"當使用某場所的免費網路，你的DNS是受到管控的，故你的瀏覽紀錄可能會被該網路提供者查詢 When using a free network, your DNS is controlled by others, so your browsing history may be queried by the the provider",
			"沒有HTTPS憑證的網站，你所輸入的資訊都有可能被中間者所竊取，故在使用陌生網路時，不應輸入任何個人資料。For websites without HTTPS certificates, the information you enter may be stolen by middlemen, so you should not enter any personal information when using untrustworthy networks.",
		],
	},
];
